functionalfoodscenter.net 2018-09-23

# FFC Privacy Policy

This privacy notice imparts the practices for <http://functionalfoodscenter.net/>. This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this website and complies with the European Union's General Data Protection Regulation. It will notify you of the following:

1.     What identifiable information is collected from you through the website, how the data is used and with whom the info may be shared.

2.     What options are immediately available to you regarding the use of your data.

3.     The security & encryption procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.

**Data Aggregation, Utilization, and Sharing**    
The Functional Food Center are the sole data controllers of the information collected on this site. We only have access to collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone.

We will use your information to respond to you, regarding the reason you contacted us. Additionally, this information may be used for statistical or research purposes. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request, e.g. to ship an order.

Unless you opt out of occasional e-mail updates, we may contact you about promotions, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy.

**Your Access to and Control Over Information  **  
You may prefer to stop any future contact from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number given on our website:

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.  

**Security  **  
We take the necessary steps to guard your information from nefarious third parties. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline. Whenever we collect any information from you such as cookies, credit card information or your e-mail address, that information is encrypted.  While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only individuals under the employment of the Functional Food Center who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or research) are granted access to identifiable information. Computers and servers in which we store personally data are kept in a secure environment.

**Registration  
** To use certain services of this website, a user must first complete a form that requires distinctive information. During registration, a potential user is required to give certain information such as name and email address. This information is used to contact you about the products or services on our site in which you have expressed interest or bought.

**Orders  **  
We request information from you on our order form. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we'll use this information to contact you.

**Cookies  **  
We and many other organizations use "cookies" on this site to improve access to our site and to identify repeat visitors. Cookies are found client-side on the user's hard drive where we can access that data for better use of our website. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information on our site.

**Sharing    
**We use an outside shipping company to ship orders such as our books, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes beyond filling your order.

**Links  **  
This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

**Information Liberties and Contact Info  
** If petitioned on the safety of your data, an employee or affiliate of Functional Food Center will provide you with information what personal data we store in relation to you. Should your personal data be incorrect, you may have it rectified or deleted at your discretion. Please direct any requests or other questions and comments regarding this privacy statement or the privacy practices to our e-mail ffc@functionalfoodcenter.com or call us at our toll-free number 1-(866)-202-0487.
